KOMAL N. RATHI

+65-97969260, komal.madhav@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Looking for an exciting opportunity in an innovation-driven organization that requires a combination of strong 'people' as well as 'technical' skills to achieve well-defined and time-bound results

CAREER SUMMARY

6+ Years of experience with proven proficiency in application development with an end-to-end exposure to development of Enterprise Software. Ploughed in by organizations to generate new solution ideas, and continuous collaboration with global teams, by virtue of strong interpersonal and communication capabilities.

CORE COMPETENCE

- Strategic and Logical Thinking
- Proactive
- Big Picture View of Business
- Taking Ownership
- Enterprising Leader
- Dedicated going beyond expectations
- An Eye for Detail
- Interpersonal sensitivity
- Planning & Execution

FUNCTIONAL COMPETENCE

- End-to-end Module Development
- Proof of concept development
- User Orientation
- Multidisciplinary Exposure Semiconductor and Banking
- Idea Generation and Implementation
- Quick Learning Capabilities
- Mentoring Team Members

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Crédit Agricole Corporate and Investment Bank, Singapore.

Key Responsibilities:

- Spearhead the most significant project of the team within the first 3 months
- Proactively propose new opportunities, techniques and approaches
- Contribute towards performance improvement and CI/CD.
- Work across projects & teams while building an inclusive culture

Software Engineer (Oct 2019 till date)

Product: Market Abuse & Detection

Tool to assist in detecting if any anomalies in the transactions for the day. Building an ETL (Extraction, Transformation and Loading) logic using Spark which led to 80% performance gain.

Tools and Languages: C#, Java, SQL, Apache Spark, Microsoft Visual Studio IDE, Git.

Samsung R&D India, Bangalore, India.

Key Responsibilities:

- Ownership of end to end product development
- A curious learner & put into effect newer technologies
- Pitching fresh ideas for new applications
- Highly adaptable team player with exceptional communication skills

Associate Staff Engineer (Mar 2018 till Oct 2019).

Product: Samsung Smart Facility

Currently working on developing component based application for the Samsung Facility. The project is based on the agile methodology of development.

Tools and Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, D3 Library, Eclipse IDE, Git.

Senior Software Engineer (Mar 2016 till Mar 2018).

Product: Tool to Tool Matching in Samsung Foundary.

This application is based on analysis of various equipments and their suppliers in the FAB (Foundary). The project was based on the agile methodology of development.

Tools and Languages: C# .NET, WPF, Infragistics, Microsoft Visual Studio IDE, Git.

Product: Correlational Analysis between Equipment data

This is a research based project on equipment data analysis in the FAB (Foundary). It is based on the analysis between alarms and the breakdowns of the equipment. Machine learning algorithms are applied along with text mining. Technologies and Languages: Python, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning

Software Engineer (July 2014 till Mar 2016).

Product: Control Software Application for Samsung Foundary.

Designed and Developed control software being used in Samsung Foundary using agile methodologies. The application was based on Unity framework and MVVM software architectural pattern.

Tools and Languages: C# .NET, WPF, Microsoft Visual Studio IDE, IBM Rational ClearCase Version Control Tool.

Product: Smart Analytics Tool in Samsung Foundary.

This application is based on equipment analysis in the FAB (Foundary). It is a tool based on IOT which does productivity analysis of the various equipment's in the FAB and help improve the yield of production. The project was based on the agile methodology of development.

Tools and Languages: C# .NET, WPF, Infragistics, Microsoft Visual Studio IDE, Git.

Product: Defect detection on a wafer being used in Samsung Foundary.

Designed and developed several modules in an application based on the defect detection on a wafer which is further used to develop chips. The project was based on the agile methodology of development. This application was based on Unity framework and MVVM software architectural pattern.

Tools and Languages: C# .NET, WPF, SharpGL, GRPC, Microsoft Visual Studio IDE, Git.

Product: Optimization of Image Processing application Developing and optimizing OpenCL algorithms for an image processing application.

Tools and Languages: OpenCL, C

Product: Understanding and development of graphics device drivers

Learning about the ARM Mali Graphics BSP and developing graphics device drivers for Exynos series of SOC.

Tools and Languages: C, C++, Unix

Achievements:

- o Design and developed production ready code with 80% performance improvement.
- o Developed highly empathetic customer relationship, and got recognized for solving their issues swiftly and efficiently
- o Received a **Spot Award** for Quick Learning and Contribution towards Developing Software Applications.
- o Received **Spot Award** for quick ramp up in a new project and commendable contribution to it in a very short span of time.
- Received a Best Practice Award for contributing significantly to the overall project development and cross collaboration among teams globally.
- o Received **Spot Award** for building a WPF team and developing several crucial modules.

Organization Building Activities

- o Heading a team for conducting organization wide activities.
- o Amongst the 39 chosen Culture 20-20 Champions across the organization.
- Part of social initiatives
- o Part of the core committee for most events to be organized
- o Conducted multiple knowledge sharing sessions amongst the team
- o Suggested and executed innovative ideas and events at the organizational level
- Recommended process changes for faster deliveries
- o Proactively helped newer team members understand and contribute to the project as quick as possible.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- B.E. (Bachelors of Engineering) in Computer Science & Engineering, 2014, 72.89% marks
 PES Institute of Technology, Bangalore
 - Project: Managing Print Services Contribution: Developed a system for multiprinter, multi-user environment connected through LAN to track the usage of each printer by all users, and measure the performance of each printer. Developed for Windows OS with .Net/C# and MySQL.
 - Project: Document Similarity Predictor Contribution: Developed a code for comparing two given documents and estimating the percentage of similarity between them.
 - Project: CRM System

Contribution: Developed a CRM system for "Loratis Institute of Career Management" using C# in Microsoft Visual Studio Environment for Windows OS.

- Project: Collision Detection Contribution: Developed a project on Computer Graphics: The graphical representation of collision detection between multiple objects.
- Project: Online Ebook System Contribution: Developed a prototype of an online eBook system to understand the steps followed in Software Engineering.

ACHIEVEMENTS AT SCHOOL AND COLLEGE

- Amongst the 6 to be chosen from college to participate in "SAP Osmosis", an event organized by SAP Labs; Developed a
 product using SAP HANA Technology.
- Cognizant Certified Student.
- o Organized and attended 'RETCOMP 2013', an International Conference.
- o Participated in 'Facebook Hackathon'. The hack was about creating an interface where an uploaded picture on facebook by a user could be edited at the same instant.
- o Participated in 'Ayana- 2013', 24hr-hackathon conducted by PESIT, Bangalore.
- Attended 'SAP Techniversity', a Technical Conference conducted by SAP Labs.
- o Participated in 'NCAT 2013'.
- Learned Bharatanatyam for 7 years.
- o Qualified 1st level of Tabla.
- o Received bronze medals in Swimming during schooling.
- o Part of the organizing committee of The Amateur Scientist 2011, an event conducted by PES Institutions.
- o Part of the organizing team of Maaya, cultural fest of college.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 5th Jan 1993

Languages Known – Hindi, Marwari, English

Marital Status - Not Married
